<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/magnetosphere_icon_0005_The.png" medium="assets/images/what-is-the-magnetosphere.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Magnetosphere/01_whatisthemagn.mp4" title="What is the Earth's magnetosphere?" headline="Dr. Jim Green is a space physicist who explains the nature of the Earth's magnetosphere.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/what-is-the-magnetosphere.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The Earth's magnetosphere is very simply the extension of the Earth's magnetic field into space. We believe that the Earth's magnetic field is generated deep in the core of the Earth. It goes right through the surface of the Earth. And we've all used compasses to determine our North and South direction, so we are familiar with the Earth's magnetic field. But we are finding that the Earth's magnetic field extends into large distances above the surface of Earth and way into space. And this is called the magnetosphere.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/magnetosphere_icon_0004_Size.png" medium="assets/images/how-large.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Magnetosphere/02_howlargeisthemag.mp4" title="How large is Earth's magnetosphere?" headline="Dr. Jim Green talks about the size of the magnetosphere relative to Earth's radius.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/how-large.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The magnetosphere is very large. If we were to use the radius of the Earth as a yardstick, if you will, the front part of the magnetosphere is about 10 to 12 Earth radii. But the tail of the magnetosphere can extend to 1,000 Earth radii or more.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/magnetosphere_icon_0003_Seein.png" medium="assets/images/can-we-see.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Magnetosphere/03_canweseemag.mp4" title="Can we see the Earth's magnetosphere?" headline="Dr. Jim Green explains how we see the effects of the magnetosphere and study it using spacecraft.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/can-we-see.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>From the beginning of time we've been able to see the effects of the Earth's magnetosphere by looking at aurora. But its only been recently that we've been able to study the Earth's magnetosphere by seeing it through a variety of new technologies that are flying on the IMAGE spacecraft that was recently launched by NASA.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/magnetosphere_icon_0006_The.png" medium="assets/images/how-sun-affects.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Magnetosphere/04_howsuneffectmag.mp4" title="How does the Sun affect the Earth's magnetosphere?" headline="Dr. Jim Green explains how the solar wind affects the Earth's magnetosphere.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/how-sun-affects.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The Sun has a dramatic effect on the Earth's magnetosphere. If we start with the Sun, not only do we receive light from the Sun, but the Sun is in a constant process of exhaling. it's losing matter, millions of tons, in all directions. This matter can be very fast or can be very slow, and we call it the solar wind. <br><br>The solar wind impacts everything in the solar system. And in the Earth's environment the first thing it hits is the Earth's magnetosphere. Much like standing in a boat and watching the waves... move around the bow of the boat, the Earth's magnetosphere pushes the solar wind to either side. But there are times when the solar wind becomes so intense that our magnetic field protection breaks down. Solar wind particles enter the magnetosphere and the Earth's response to that is for ionospheric material to also erupt from the top of our ionosphere and also merge with the solar wind material that's in our magnetosphere.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/magnetosphere_icon_0002_Earth.png" medium="assets/images/earth-without-magnetosphere.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Magnetosphere/05_whatifnomagfield.mp4" title="What would happen if Earth didn't have a magnetosphere?" headline="Dr. Jim Green takes a look at planets without magnetospheres to imagine what might happen to Earth without its magnetic field.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/earth-without-magnetosphere.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>What would happen if the Earth did not have a magnetic field? It wouldn't have the protection of the magnetosphere that it currently does. That means the solar wind would impact directly on the Earths ionosphere and upper atmosphere. <br><br>One way we can look at what would happen and speculate what would happen would be to look at other planets that do not have magnetospheres but have ionospheres and atmospheres. The perfect planet to look at would be Mars. It's about the same size as the Earth, a little smaller, but indeed it has no magnetic field, but an extensive atmosphere and ionosphere. <br><br>What we find is the solar wind as it impacts the ionosphere, begins to strip away a number of the larger molecules, such as water, oxygen, and that flows back into the solar wind. We've made an estimate of how much water, based on the solar wind direct interaction on Mars, that Mars has lost over the last several billion years, and we believe it can be as much as fifty meters of global ocean that has been lost from Mars over the last 3,000,000,000 to 4,000,000,000 years.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/magnetosphere_icon_0001_Study.png" medium="assets/images/study-changes.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Magnetosphere/06_canstudentsstudy.mp4" title="How can students study changes in the magnetosphere?" headline="Dr. Jim Green explains how the aurora reflects changes in Earth's magnetic field?">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/study-changes.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>There are several ways students can study the changes that occur in the magnetosphere. If you're lucky to live in Canada or Alaska or a number of the Northern latitude countries in Europe and Russia, you'd be able to see and observe the aurora. And it's during these auroral events, which are particles that are raining on our upper atmosphere, that are describing or telling us about the changes that are occurring in the magnetosphere, due to the break down of the protection that it provides us to the solar wind. <br><br>Another way to study the magnetosphere is during these intense geomagnetic storms. Currents arise in the magnetosphere. These currents can be measured on the Earth. And with a very simple, let's say, a soda-pop magnetometer you can actually measure the deflection of the Earth's magnetic field caused by these currents in the magnetosphere.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/magnetosphere_icon_0000_Venus.png" medium="assets/images/venus.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Magnetosphere/07_doesvenushavemag.mp4" title="Does Venus have a magnetosphere?" headline="Dr. Jim Green gives a possible reason that Venus lacks a magnetic field.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/venus.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Venus unfortunately does not have a magnetosphere. We've visited Venus on many occasions with appropriate equipment to be able to measure the magnetic field, but unfortunately it does not. So the solar wind impacts directly on the upper ionosphere and atmosphere of Venus. Why Venus doesn't have a magnetosphere, we're not quite sure of. However, there must be significant differences between the core material of Venus from the Earth's core. <br><br>Now we believe the Earth generates its magnetic field due to a liquid iron core, that is moving at a different speed than our rotational speed. So therefore, we believe that Venus' core must be rotating at approximately the same rate that the planet does.</p>]]></description>
	</media>

</xml>