<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0000_What-is-an.png" medium="assets/images/what_is_aurora.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Aurora/01_whatisanaurora.mp4" title="What is an aurora?" headline="Dr. Nicola Fox talks about the nature and history of Auroras.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/what_is_aurora.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>An aurora is a beautiful pattern of lights in the sky. They tend to look like a billowing curtain being blown in the wind. You see beautiful colors, beautiful wisps and different structures. And just like snowflakes, no two aurora are ever alike.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0003_Where-to-see.png" medium="assets/images/how_far_south.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Aurora/02_wherecanIsee.mp4" title="How far south can you see the Northern Lights?" headline="Dr. Nicola Fox talks about unusual auroral events that happen as far south as Texas and Florida.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/how_far_south.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Typically the Aurora will stay around the arctic circle. But when we have particularly large events, usually once or twice every 10 years, they can track as far south as maybe as Texas or Florida. There was one big aurora that occurred in March of 1989 that was clearly visible from both Texas and Florida. And then also one slightly more recently in July of 2000, which also would have been visible from there but sadly it occurred a little bit too early in the day, and the Sun was still up. So we were able to see them with our space-based cameras, but sadly nobody on the ground was able to see them.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0002_Why-are-auro.png" medium="assets/images/aurora_different_colors.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Aurora/03_whyareaurorasdiff.mp4" title="Why are auroras different colors?" headline="Dr. Nicola Fox explains how different elements in the atmosphere cause auroral colors.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/aurora_different_colors.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The Auroras can be almost any different color. There are different atoms in our own atmosphere... that actually cause these different colors. The most common one is an oxygen atom. The particles, the electrons come smashing in from outside our immediate atmosphere and collide with these oxygen atoms and cause them to get excited and then as they relax back to their beginning state they let out light. Oxygen tends to let out a green light, although sometimes it can let out red. Nitrogen will let out a blue light. And when all these colors mixed together you can get beautiful purples, mauves, even white. So you can get some really spectacular colors in the sky.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0001_Best-place.png" medium="assets/images/where_to_see_aurora.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Aurora/04_howfarsouth.mp4" title="Where can I see an aurora?" headline="Dr. Nicola Fox encourages viewers to go to the poles if they want to see an aurora.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/where_to_see_aurora.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The most likely place to go and see an aurora will be anywhere where it is cold, anywhere around the arctic circle. Somewhere between Canada or the top states of the United States. Anywhere through Scandinavia, through Russia, basically anywhere where it is very cold. In addition to being able to see them in the North, you can also see them in the Southern Hemisphere. In fact there are two auroras, the Aurora Borealis and Australis. So anywhere in Australia, Antarctica and New Zealand, all great places to see the aurora.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0005_The-Earth.png" medium="assets/images/earth_sun_auroras.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Aurora/05_aurora_sunearthconnection.mp4" title="What can an aurora tell us about the Sun-Earth connection?" headline="Dr. Nicola Fox discusses how the connection between Sun and Earth causes aurora.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/earth_sun_auroras.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>When you see an aurora, you know that we are having a Sun-Earth Connection event. We know that all the energy from the Sun is somehow being harnessed in our own atmosphere, and is causing great amounts of energy to flow or electric currents to flow around our near space atmosphere. In the same way you would switch on a fluorescent light and you would have an electric current that passes through the gas, that is usually argon maybe, and it causes each of those molecules to actually emit light. And that's why a fluorescent light tube is on. That is actually what is happening with the aurora. You have current flowing through our atmosphere and causing all those lights to switch on.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0004_Auroras-and.png" medium="assets/images/aurora_solar_wind.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Aurora/06_auroras_solarwind.mp4" title="What is the connection between auroras and the solar wind?" headline="Dr. Nicola Fox explains how the contact between the solar wind and Earth's magnetic field causes auroras.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/aurora_solar_wind.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The solar wind harnesses the power that actually drives aurora. One of the early theories was the particles that were carried along with the solar wind actually directly caused the aurora. Now, we have a lot more observations, we know now that that's not true. And the particles that actually cause the aurora themselves are from our own magnetic atmosphere. We call it the magnetosphere. The Earth has a magnetic field that actually protects us from all of the nasty radiation that comes from Sun, and it basically carves out a cavity in the solar wind that keeps our planet safe. When certain conditions are favorable, all of the energy from the solar wind can enter this magnetic cavity and cause great reconfigurations of our own magnetic field. And you will get an imbalance. There's too much magnetic field on one side and not enough on the other. And nature always will redress a balance. So processes will take place to actually move those magnetic fields back up and get our happy balance back. And during this reconfiguration these electrons in our own atmosphere get accelerated to incredible high energies, and they smash into the atoms of our own atmosphere, oxygen and nitrogen in particular, and cause them to be excited. When they are excited they will eventually relax back to their original state, and as they are doing so they let off a photon of light or a bundle of energy that we see as light and that's the colors you see in the aurora.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0006_Auroras-in.png" medium="assets/images/daytime_auroras.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Aurora/07_cantseeinday.mp4" title="Why can't we see auroras in the daytime?" headline="Dr. Nicola Fox talks about how the light of the Sun washes out auroral lights.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/daytime_auroras.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>We can't see the auroras with our own eyes in the day because the light of the Sun is so much greater. So you just can't see anything during daylight. However, one key thing as well as emitting these blue, green, and red light, the aurora also emit in ultraviolet. And while you can't see that again with your own eyes, we can see that with spacecraft that fly in space. We are able to look down, see the whole Earth, and then we can actually subtract the sunlight and we're just left at what the aurora looks like in ultraviolet. So one of the big advances we have had with space-based technology is now allowing us to look at global aurora and not just the pieces we can see with our naked eyes.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_myths_thumb.png" medium="assets/images/aurora_myths.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Aurora/08_legends_myths.mp4" title="Are there legends or myths associated with the aurora?" headline="Dr. Nicola Fox lists different legends from around the world based on the aurora.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/aurora_myths.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Since almost the beginning of time since people first observed the aurora there's been lots of myths and legends associated with it. Initially in China and in Europe, the aurora, the sort of wisps and trails that you would see in the sky were associated with dragons. One of the Chinese dragon myths is actually called the 'Candle Dragon' and it's based on the aurora. And there's also people say that maybe the English patron saint, Sir George, instead of actually killing a dragon, it was merely an aurora sited over Scotland. That was probably one of the most early ones. A lot of them have been associated with gods. Some people think it is associated with Freya, the Goddess of Love. Sorry, Freya, the Goddess of Love. Then also it's thought to be the bridge, the burning bridge which actually led the gods from the heavens to the Earth, in particular, Thor, the God of War. So that whenever it was seen it was seen with quite a lot of worry. A little later, Native American Indians thought it were the souls of warriors fighting in the sky. Eskimos, slightly nicer, thought it was souls at play using a walrus head as a ball. Even if it wasn't associated with mythical creatures, or the souls of dead relatives... In Scandinavia, whenever they saw a bright aurora, they thought it would tell that it would be very cold and a lot of snow would come. And conversely to that, when the Eskimos saw it, they thought finally that the winter would be over and nice weather would be coming.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
</xml>