<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/06_solarfusion_thumb.png" medium="assets/images/Solar-Fusion.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Visualizations/06_solarfusion.mp4" title="Solar Fusion" headline="Nuclear reactions in the Sun's core produce its energy.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Solar-Fusion.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Nuclear reactions in the Sun's core produce its energy.  Hydrogen fuses together to make helium and other higher-level elements.  And when you have nuclear reaction occurring, you get even more energy given off and energy is heat.  And at the center of the Sun, it's roughly 15,000,000 degrees but as it moves out the heat and light fight their way through dense plasma and magnetic fields towards the Sun's visible surface, so the heat diffuses. Visualization courtesy of Solarmax: Museum of Science and Industry.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
					
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/01_under_sunspots_thumb.png" medium="assets/images/aia304.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Visualizations/01_under_sunspots.mp4" title="Sunspot Temperatures" headline="Plasma Temperatures Under Sunspots">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/aia304.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Sunspots are darker, cooler regions on the Sun's surface. This animation shows the subsurface temperature profile around a sunspot. The red areas denote higher than average temperature, while the blue areas directly under the spots are cooler than average.  Data from the Michelson Doppler Imager (MDI) instrument on the SOHO spacecraft has helped reveal these differences in temperature under sunspots. The MDI instrument measures the speed of sound waves as they travel through the Sun. Sound travels faster through hotter regions and slower through cooler areas. Visualization courtesy of NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center Scientific Visualization Studio.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
				
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/02_multimission_thumb.png" medium="assets/images/Solar-Flare.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Visualizations/02_multimission.mp4" title="View of a Solar Flare" headline="View of a Solar Flare">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Solar-Flare.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>A variety of NASA spacecraft and instruments provide a unique view of a solar flare on April 21, 2002. Solar flares emit high-energy atomic particles and electromagnetic radiation into space.  The time scales of the imagery vary from as long 6 hours to as short as 12 seconds. A total of 7 instruments from NASA's Solar and Heliospheric Observatory (SOHO), Transition Region and Coronal Explorer (TRACE), and the Reuven Ramaty High Energy Solar Spectroscopic Imager (RHESSI) provide the data for this visualization.  Visualization courtesy of NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center Scientific Visualization Studio.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
				
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/03_coronalmass_thumb.png" medium="assets/images/Coronal-Mass-Ejection.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Visualizations/03_nwcoronalmass.mp4" title="Coronal Mass Ejection" headline="Coronal Mass Ejection">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Coronal-Mass-Ejection.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>A coronal mass ejection (CME) is a vast magnetic blob of high-energy particles that erupts from the Sun's corona and travels through space at high speed. The cloud of particles carries with it a magnetic field. If a CME heads in the direction of Earth, its magnetic field interacts with the Earth's magnetosphere.  The magnetosphere protects us from charged solar particles.  Visualization courtesy of NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center Scientific Visualization Studio.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
</xml>
