<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<category>
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/09_polar_thumb.png" medium="assets/images/Auroral-activity.png" source="http://ds9.ssl.berkeley.edu/imageviewer/images/images2/latest_pmapN_full.jpg" title="Auroral Activity on Earth" headline="Auroral Activity on Earth - NOAA POES" showEarthScale="no" widget="no">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Auroral-activity.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>This image shows the extent of auroral activity near the north geographic pole. The images are extrapolated from the most recent polar pass of the NOAA POES satellite. You should be able to see an auroral 'oval,' roughly centered on the north magnetic pole. Bright areas in this region are the 'Northern Lights' or aurora. During intense magnetic storms, the aurora can expand to lower latitudes causing brilliant auroras across the lower United States.  Data supplied courtesy of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's Space Environment Center.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
				
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/01_allsky_thumb.png" medium="assets/images/Kiruna.png" source="http://www.irf.se/allsky/LAST.JPG" title="Kiruna All-Sky camera" headline="Latest image from the Kiruna All-Sky camera" showEarthScale="no" widget="no">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Kiruna.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>An all-sky camera has been operating in Kiruna since the International Geophysical Year in 1957 (Stoffregen, 1962). In 1977 the camera was replaced with a new more automated type. The new digital all-sky camera in Kiruna is based on a commercial digital camera with replaceable optics. The camera is controlled by one computer and the image data is then transferred to an archiving computer, where it is made available to the web. (with a 1-2 day delay). The sky is imaged onto a convex mirror, which is photographed by the 16 mm film camera located above the mirror. The film camera is controlled by electronics, which exposes the camera at a selected interval (typically once every minute), synchronizes the exposures with UTC (using GPS), and advances the film, etc. Typical exposure time is 4 seconds, but every eighth exposure is four times longer, in order to reveal faint auroras. When the camera is not in use, or during heavy snowfall, a cover automatically closes and protects the mirror. An electrical heater keeps the mirror free of mist.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
</category>