<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/what_is_the_solar_wind.png" medium="assets/images/What-is-solar-wind.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Solar%20Wind/01_whatissolarwind.mp4" title="What is the Solar Wind?" headline="Dr. Sten Odenwald discusses the nature of the solar wind and how the Sun compares to other stars">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/What-is-solar-wind.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Well, the solar wind, if you were in it, is first of all, is invisible. But if you have the right type of detectors you can actually see the individual particles that are coming at you. Now, for the most part for what the solar wind is mostly the outer layers of the Sun coming at you. And that material is pretty much what is called a plasma, and it has almost the same composition as the Sun. That is to say it is mostly hydrogen and helium, nuclei, a lot of electrons, and a variety of ions of various types. It is called a plasma because it's one of what you would call the fourth state of matter. You have solid, liquid, and gas, and then you have plasma. You can think of them as basically things that are heated to different temperatures. Solid form is at a very low temperature. A liquid, the atoms are bit more mobile, and can move around a little bit. When you get into a gas, the atoms are moving much more rapidly. They're not encountering each other too often, and the whole collection acts sort of like, well, like a gas, for lack of a better word. When you get into a plasma the temperatures are so hot that the atoms are moving so fast that they are slam into each other and can liberate the electrons from some of these atoms. And the atoms then become charged and they are called ions. And so you wind up with a real mess, actually. You wind up with neutral particles and these ionized atoms, and then you have all these electrons that are sort of flowing around. It's a complicated thing also, because very often, there is a magnetic field that can be present in the solar wind at the same time. This field comes from the Sun. From loops of magnetic energy from the Sun that are sort of trapped in the plasma as it flows out into space. The solar wind is a plasma; it has pretty much the same composition as the Sun in terms of the types of atoms. But it is in a very high temperature state and moving at millions of miles an hour out into the solar system. Also by the time this plasma gets out beyond Pluto, it rams against what is called the interstellar medium and you form this big shock. It is a shock front, is what they call it. It is kind of like a jet plane moving very rapidly through the air. it forms this shock and you can hear it at the ground it sounds like a sonic boom. Well, the Sun is doing the same thing. you got the solar wind flowing out, it meets up against the interstellar medium, and produces the same kind of a thing. In fact, the voyager spacecraft, both of them, have actually begun to detect signs of this shock front, which is very exciting.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/why_monitor_solar_wind.png" medium="assets/images/Why-do-we-monitor.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Solar%20Wind/02_monitorsolarwind.mp4" title="Why do we monitor the solar wind?" headline="Dr. Sten Odenwald talks about how the solar wind interacts with the Earth's magnetic field.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Why-do-we-monitor.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The reason why we monitor the solar wind is not so much to prevent satellite damage, because the wind itself doesn't damage satellites. The Earth's magnetic field manages to shield us rather well from the solar wind or at least the direct particles from the wind. What we want instead is to understand how the solar wind... causes changes in the Earth's magnetic field, causing particles that are already there to get accelerated to high energies. And then those particles are the ones that effect satellites. So it's a kind of a two-step thing, and it's the wind not doing something directly but in a sort of a back door way. The wind sets up the conditions for the Earth as a generator of things to create the particles that then do the damage. The exception are things like high-energy proton events from the Sun which are a type of solar flare event. Those particles stream directly into the satellite, and that doesn't even matter if the Earth has a field. So we want to monitor the solar wind as a way of assessing whether or not there is a bad storm on the way. And once we know that's the case, then we understand certain things about how bad storms affect the Earth and the particles that are already there. Particles such as the ones that arein the Van Allen Radiation Belts for instance, or in other clouds of plasma that are in the Earth's environment. Those are the ones that get pumped up in energy to thousands and millions of volts and then they do the damage to satellites that happen to be in the same place.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
</xml>