<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0000_How-big-is-the.png" medium="assets/images/how_big_is_sun.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/01_howbigisthesun.mp4" title="How big is the Sun?" headline="Dr. Art Poland talks about the volume of the Sun and its size relative to Earth.">
	<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/how_big_is_sun.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The size of the Sun is overwhelming when you think about it. The Earth is 5,000 kilometers and we always think of the Earth as being really big. But if you were to look at the Sun you can fit 100 Earths across the Sun. What that means if you look at it in another way is volume. You can fit over 1,000,000 Earths inside the Sun. If you look at a picture of the Sun and you are seeing all kinds of features on it the Earth's size would be just one little speck, or one little dot on the Sun. So the Sun is much, much bigger than the Earth.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
				
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0001_Why-is-the-sun.png" medium="assets/images/Why-is-the-sun-hot_.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/02_whyisthesunhot.mp4" title="Why is the Sun hot?" headline="Dr. Art Poland explains nuclear energy generation and how it makes the Sun hot.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Why-is-the-sun-hot_.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>So you want to know why the Sun is hot. Well, it's hot because of nuclear energy generation. It's really interesting and fun how the Sun was formed, it was a bunch of diffused gasses and they condensed because of the gravitational attraction, and as you get the gasses pulling closer and closer together the pressure goes up, the temperature goes up, and when it gets enough pressure, and dense enough, and hot enough, it starts to have nuclear reactions. That's hydrogen joined together to make helium and other higher-level elements. And when you have nuclear reaction occurring, you get even more energy given off and energy is heat. And actually at the center of the Sun, it's like 15,000,000 degrees but as it moves out it gets more, more diffused. At the surface, the surface temperature of the Sun is about 5,000 degrees, and that's what we see, is 5,000 degrees. Some interesting aspects about it is, that if it were cooler, like say 3,000 degrees, it would look redder. And if it were hotter, like 20,000 degrees it would look bluer. So the color is also an indication in fact of how hot it is. In fact, that's how we measure the temperature of the sun is by measuring exactly what color it is.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0003_What-are-sunspo.png" medium="assets/images/sunspots_2.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/03_whataresunspots.mp4" title="What are sunspots?" headline="Dr. Art Poland talks about the sun's magnetic field and how variations in it cause sunspots.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/sunspots_2.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Sunspots are a really interesting phenomenon on the Sun. They're areas of strong magnetic field and magnetic field is probably the most interesting aspect of physics that we are going to get out of the Sun. Maybe I shouldn't have said that, because there's also nuclear physics at the core but at least for my research the magnetic field is the most interesting thing. And how that magnetic field is generated, how it evolves, how it changes with time and the kinds of physical processes that occur in the magnetic field. are what we're are interested in and the sunspot is right there at the surface. What we're seeing there is the effect of the magnetic field on the photosphere.  Now, what we are pretty sure is happening is that the magnetic field is reducing the effectiveness of convection, the transfer of energy from below the atmosphere to the top of the atmosphere. And what happens is the magnetic field reduces the convection, makes it so that the sunspot's not so hot, so it looks cooler, so it looks dark. Now, that sunspot is actually hot, its 4,000 degrees instead of 5,000 degrees. But it's like looking at a faint light bulb next to a bright light bulb. The faint light bulb doesn't look bright just because the bright light bulb is there. You take the bright light bulb away, the faint light bulb looks bright. Sunspots are the same way. It's surrounded by hotter material so it looks dark. But if you took the hotter material away, it will still be bright.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0004_What-is-the-sol.png" medium="assets/images/solar-cycles.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/04_whatissolarcycle.mp4" title="What is the solar cycle?" headline="Dr. Art Poland talks about the nature of the Sun and solar cycle.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/solar-cycles.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The solar cycle is an 11-year cycle of magnetic change on the Sun. It's primarily looked at in terms of sunspots. When you have a minimum number of sunspots we call that solar minimum. Then you go through a period where there are more and more sunspots on the Sun, you see an increase in the number, greater and greater as you go along until about five years after minimum you have a maximum number of sunspots. A lot of change on the Sun, a lot of evolution. Then after this maximum, it decreases again and you get less and less sunspots and you go back down to minimum. During maximum is when you have the most flares and the most magnetic activity. Another interesting thing seems to be associated with that, is that the Sun goes through an 11-year cycle, maximum, minimum, maximum, minimum. There were two periods that we know about back in the middle 1600s and early 1500s when the sunspot cycle seemed to have stopped. Let's say there were no maximum, no minimum. The Sun was just sitting there. During those times in Northern Europe there were many ice ages. The climate on the Earth had changed and Northern Europe was colder during those times. We have no idea why that happened. We also have no idea what causes the sunspot cycle. We have an idea, we're beginning to get an idea of what causes sunspots in terms of the turbulence and the interface between the core of the Sun, or the radiative zone, we call it, and the convective zone, which is, say, about a third of the distance from the top. There seems to be a shear there and there is turbulence as the Sun rotates. The Sun rotates at different velocities at that area, and that seems to cause the magnetic field. But why that changes with time, we have no idea at all.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0005_Solar-Flares-an.png" medium="assets/images/CMEs.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/05_whataresolarflares_cmes.mp4" title="What are solar flares?" headline="Dr. Art Poland explains how magnetic field fluctuations cause solar flares and coronal mass ejections.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/CMEs.png"" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>I'm going to talk about solar flares a little bit and coronal mass ejections. And it's kind of a fun topic because some scientists say, "Solar flares cause coronal mass ejections,\" and other scientists say "No, you can have a coronal mass ejection without a flare,\" and it gets into a really fun scientific argument. But let me just say that they're both magnetic activity on the Sun, and it has to do with the rate of that activity. A flare is very rapid. You get a very rapid release of energy, of the magnetic field energy. The temperatures go up very high, you get x-rays given off, sometimes you even get gamma rays given off. Temperatures get up to 10,000,000 to 20,000,000 of degrees, really hot, very rapidly, and then it will cool down again. A coronal mass ejection can happen with a flare, but sometimes a coronal mass ejection will be just the magnetic field slowly erupting and ejecting magnetic energy and material particles out into space. Kind of like a cloud of materials flying out into space. It travels at about 200 to 1,000 kilometers per second. Typically takes about two days. If it's aimed at the Earth, two days after, you'll get a coronal mass ejection. You'll get particles and magnetic field hitting the Earth, causing changes in the Earth's  magnetosphere, and things like that.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0002_Learning-from-t.png" medium="assets/images/What-do-we-hope-to-learn_.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/06_whatdohopetolearn.mp4" title="What do we hope to learn about the sun?" headline="Dr. Art Poland discusses the solar physical processes we study and why.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/What-do-we-hope-to-learn_.png"" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The main thing we want to learn is, from my viewpoint, is new physical processes. There are things going on in the Sun. Its scale is so different than the Earth, in terms of temperature, size, magnetic fields. There are things we can't reproduce in the laboratory. And I as a physicist like to study new things, new physical processes. And in terms of what we hope to learn, I can't say exactly. Yes, I want to  learn about, for example, new energy sources of magnetic fields. I might be able to say something like that. But what we're going to discover I can't say, because we haven't discovered it yet. But that's the exciting thing about science, from my viewpoint, is to discover the unknown. And the Sun is a laboratory where we can discover things that we just can't discover on Earth.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0006_The-Sun-vs. Oth.png" medium="assets/images/Sun-vs.-stars.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/07_howthesuncompares.mp4" title="How does the sun compare to other stars?" headline="Dr. Sten Odenwald refutes the idea that the Sun is just an average star.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Sun-vs.-stars.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The Sun compares to other stars in kind of an interesting way. I mean we always talk about things being sort of average. And it is often said that the Sun is an average star. It's average in one way and not average in another. For instance, it's not average in brightness. Most of the stars in the sky, in the galaxy, in the Milk Way galaxy, are somewhat fainter than the Sun. As in, they produce a bit less power. It's like comparing a 100 watt light bulb as the Sun and a typical star is maybe a 40 watt bulb. So the Sun is not average in terms of that. It's not average in terms of size either, because again, most of the stars in the Milky Way are smaller and redder in terms of numbers.  You know, by a show of hands, and averages are based on a show of hands. But we call the Sun average because sort of historically that's what we have always done. It is actually a little bit above average.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0007_Voyages-through.png" medium="assets/images/Voyages.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/Nature_Voyager_NASA_H.264_720.mp4" title="Voyages through the heliosphere." headline="The twin Voyager spacecraft, launched in 1977 to travel to and explore Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune, have made many intriguing discoveries, including a possible ocean of liquid water on one of Jupiter's moons.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Voyages.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>The Voyager mission has been exploring our solar system for decades. Now, Nature reveals some of its latest findings. I personally feel like it's the greatest mission of exploration that was ever launched. It's been to so many planets, discovered so many things, and now it's still discovering things 30 years after it was launched. Nature has just published six papers about the giant bubble the sun creates around itself called the heliosphere, and five of those papers depend on data from the Voyager 2 spacecraft. That spacecraft was launched in August of 1977 on a journey to the giant outer planets- Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune.  Neptune, the outmost, is 30 times as far from the sun as the Earth, and, today,  Voyager 2 is over 80 times as far from the sun as the Earth, and at the very outer reaches of this giant bubble. And we are trying to reach outside of that bubble into interstellar space, and both Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 are on a journey to be the first to reach interstellar space. Nobody has been in interstellar space in our lifetime. There probably will not be another mission that's going to go there, so Voyager crossing into the final frontier is very exciting for scientists and probably for the public as well.  Without the sun, life would not exist. We would not be here asking the questions about it. We count on the sun for everything we are, and everything we know as familiar to us here on the Earth. And it's our star that's determining our environment, our existence. We're almost obliged as intellectual beings to ask the question why is it there and how does it work? The sun like all stars, creates a bubble around itself, and it's that bubble that the interaction from the wind from other stars and our own sun interact. And we are now in the outer layer of that bubble, where that interaction takes place.  So for the first time, we're now able to observe how our star interacts with what came from other stars outside. The solar wind is a stream of particles flowing away from the upper atmosphere of the sun. It expands to a long distance. The solar wind expands against the interstellar medium, creates a cavity that holds our solar system. This cavity is called the heliosphere. You can make a heliosphere in your kitchen sink by just running the water into but not right directly in the drain, but to the side of the drain, and as the water comes down and hits the bottom of the pan and begins to rush out in all directions, pretty much equally, but not quite equally, but it rushes straight out, and it pushes back the water that's in the pan. It's makes a little circle, or almost a circle. And the reason that it can't just push forever and just clean out the whole thing is because as it rushes out, it just decreases in pressure,  and it can't push back all that water, and so there's a finite extent to it. And that's the same thing that's happening in our heliosphere. The solar wind is rushing out, pushing back on the ions and the magnetic field of the galaxy, making a little bubble in it. And the other thing about it is the edge of the circle is very turbulent and rough. The solar wind plasma and the interstellar plasma are coming and colliding  with one another, basically, and they're producing this very complicated boundary layer of the inter heliosheath and the outer heliosheath, and the termination shock between them. Voyager 2 has five key instruments on it to measure the environment in this huge bubble that's around the sun.  The key measurement has to do with the wind coming from the sun.   The solar atmosphere is evaporating and speeding away at a million miles per hour, creating this giant bubble, and one of our instruments measures that wind. We measure it every day, looking for evidence that we have reached the outer edge of the supersonic solar wind. These three measures measure the ions, the ionized atoms, which fill the outer part of the heliosphere.  But we also measure the magnetic field, which is carried out by that ionized wind, as well as the waves in that wind called plasmas waves. The instrument which measures the magnetic fields is actually on a boom, which projects out this way 13 meters, 43 feet, to get it away from the spacecraft, itself, which contaminates the very weak field we're trying to measure.  And the other instrument has two 10-meter-long antennas, one of which is here, and that measures the low frequency waves in the wind, which tells us something important about the wind, itself. We've been studying something called the anomalous cosmic rays with our instrument. These anomalous cosmic rays come from deep in our galaxy  and have no electrical charge. Somehow, at the heliosphere's termination shock, they've been accelerated to a high energy. But Alan Cummings found surprising data from both Voyagers. There will be more particles at low energy and fewer at high energy, and there would be a certain way that should look, and that didn't happen, and we were really astounded.  It didn't happen with Voyager 1, and so some theories were put forward,  well, maybe, you know, it was a transient from the sun just at the right time that caused those particles to kind of be disrupted in their acceleration, and we didn't see them. If it had been a quiet period, we would have seen what we expected to see.  So we said, ‘Okay, well, we'll have another chance with Voyager 2.' So Voyager 2 went through the shock—same thing. We didn't see what we expected to see at all.  And so the origin, the source, where these particles are accelerated is a big mystery, and one of the big mysteries of the termination shock process. One of the interesting surprises from the Voyager solar wind instrument was that we expected all of that energy from the million-mile-per-hour wind when it abruptly stopped or slowed down, to heat the wind, itself, to a million degrees. And what we found, instead, the wind was only 100,000 degrees after it had slowed down. Most of the energy, 80% of the energy went somewhere else. Meanwhile, closer to the Earth, a pair of satellites called STEREO were launched to find out just how the sun's influence affects our planet. It as not thought in any shape or form that it would make a contribution to the understanding of the boundary between the solar wind and the interior stellar medium, which was so distant from STEREO's orbit. But STEREO had very capable instruments, and when you design a capable instrument, you're not quite sure exactly what you're going to get when you finally get into space. Space is full of stuff. The Berkeley team was surprised when STEREO's STE instrument, designed to measure low energy electrons,  seemed to be receiving another kind of signal. It was obviously detecting something else that was out in space. It could have been the spacecraft background, it could have been some detector flaw or faults, but graduate student, Linghua, with a bit of sleuthing, scientific sleuthing, was able to draw out the fact that this, in fact, was a signal from the termination shock at great distances from the STEREO spacecraft, and we were, in fact, detecting some particles that were very complementary to the Voyager measurements, in the sense that they were giving information that Voyager, itself,  could not achieve right at the site of the termination shock. It's really quite remarkable that this spacecraft,  which was launched when the space age, itself, was only 20-years-old, is now been operating for over 30 years on its journey to interstellar space. We're now exploring new areas that have never been explored before and will not be explored for many, many years, generations, probably. By the time the Voyagers run out of power in 2020, we should have crossed into interstellar space with at least one spacecraft, and we should be about 15 billion miles from Earth. They will be constantly watching what Voyager is seeing around the next bend. So, for example, when the sun becomes active again in the next solar maximum a few years from now, there will be coronal mass ejections heading outward and colliding with the termination shock, probably causing disturbances to it, changes of shape. It's expected to be a very dynamic boundary, and so we may, in fact, pass in and out of it several times even before Voyager is truly in, in an interstellar space that's unadulterated by anything the sun has to throw out. Well, I think all of us feel we've been very fortunate to have been on a journey of discovery. Even if it had stopped in 1989 with Neptune, we would have had an immensely valuable mission. But for it to continue now for decades and be the first to reach interstellar space, I think it's just an incredible journey of discovery, and we're all very fortunate to have been part of it.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/sun_icon_0008_The-End-of-a-So.png" medium="assets/images/Sun-sets-on-solar-mission.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/The%20Sun/UlyssesEOM.mp4" title="The end of a solar mission" headline="Ulysses was the first mission to survey the space environment above and below the poles of the sun. The reams of data Ulysses returned have forever changed the way scientists view our star and its effects.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Sun-sets-on-solar-mission.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Five, four, three, two, one... Ignition and lift-off of Discovery and the Ulysses spacecraft bound for the polar regions of the sun. It was a dawn launch and it was quite spectacular. ESA built the spacecraft. The operations have been performed jointly by both an ESA team and a JPL team working at JPL.  The sun has a big effect on space, including Earth, and it's the star that's nearest to us. Ulysses is a mission that is very unique in that it is exploring the sun's atmosphere at all latitudes. Be very important to see what's going on in the third dimension and particularly over the poles of the sun.  We've learned about the sun's magnetic field, how it influences the origin of the solar wind and its subsequent evolution. We've learned about how the sun accelerates particles.  We were able to see that those particles are able to essentially access all regions surrounding the sun, and the way in which it creates this heliosphere. It interacts with interstellar matter coming in.  Some of the discoveries that we really didn't anticipate -  one of them was the comet tails, we were quite surprised. We knew that there was a huge comet out there called Hyakutake and  we didn't go anywhere near that comet but to our great surprise we ended passing through the tail of the comet. But nobody anticipated how long it could be. They stretched from out further in the distance from the sun to the Earth and that was why we were able to pass through the tail.  Ulysses was definitely worth it. It was a small spacecraft. It was a very inexpensive mission, had a small operating team and it returned tremendous amount of data, new discoveries of the sun and the heliosphere things that never would have been known had we not flown a mission like Ulysses over the poles of the sun. Given that the scientific data that has been returned from Ulysess over the course of the mission is going to be used for decades to come, it is also a moment of great pride for all of the team. So I was the first person to be assigned to the mission by NASA by JPL and I've been with it this whole time. So it's been 30 years, a big part of my career, I've been doing other things as well, but this has been an exceptional opportunity and my plan is to continue on until the end of the mission and I expect to be the last person to be here. I'm going to turn off the lights (laughs).</p>]]></description>
	</media>
				
</xml>