<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0000_The-edge-of.png" medium="assets/images/heliosphere_uno.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Heliosphere/Heliopause1.mp4" title="What is meant by the edge of the solar system?" headline="Dr. Merav Opher talks about the heliopause, the distant region where the solar wind collides with the interstellar medium.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/heliosphere_uno.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>We're thinking about the region beyond the termination shock. And the termination shock is a region where the supersonic solar wind go through a shock You can think about a big waterfall that the solar wind goes and starts slowing down as it's approaching the interstellar medium. Now the heliopause is what separates us from the rest of the galaxy, the interstellar medium. So the Sun with its wind, it's curved like a bubble in the interstellar medium and the wind coming from the sun clashes against the interstellar medium and forms this boundary that we call the heliopause.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0003_What-mission.png" medium="assets/images/Missions.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Heliosphere/Heliopause2.mp4" title="What missions provided the data?" headline="Dr. Merav Opher talks about the Voyager and IBEX missions' role in providing data about the heliosphere.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Missions.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>So the missions that we are learning about this very interesting region are coming from two different  spacecrafts. One is the Voyager spacecrafts that were launched in 1977. So it took them 30 years to arrive there. And you have also the IBEX mission that was just launched in 2008 October and got the first maps of the  energetic neutrals. So we are learning from these two different  missions. Voyager is measuring in situ. So it's right there measuring. And the IBEX is looking at the global view about the same region.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0002_Learning-abo.png" medium="assets/images/What-are-we-learning.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Heliosphere/Heliopause3.mp4" title="What are we learning about the edge of the solar system?" headline="Dr. Merav Opher explains how the interstellar magnetic field shapes our heliosphere.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/What-are-we-learning.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Our heliosphere is asymmetric; it is not identical in the northern hemisphere and the southern hemisphere.  Or in the east and west. The reason for that is interstellar magnetic field that is pushing and  shaping how we look from outside.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0005_Learning-fro.png" medium="assets/images/New-knowledge.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Heliosphere/Heliopause4.mp4" title="How will this new knowledge improve our understanding?" headline="Dr. Merav Opher explains how the knowledge we're gaining will increase our understanding of the behavior of ionized matter.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/New-knowledge.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>So the new knowledge that we are gathering from this new data and new observations are going to help us understand the whole heliosphere, and also some processes even close to the Sun. For example, what I mentioned earlier,  about the acceleration of particles. The fact that particles may be not as simple as going through a shock and accelerating particles. Maybe you have them accelerated in the sides of shocks or maybe in sheaths in coronal mass ejections. This knowledge we are gathering at the edge of the solar system probably will influence the edge but also other ionized matter.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0001_How-the-data.png" medium="assets/images/Consequences.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Heliosphere/Heliopause5.mp4" title="Are there consequences in other fields?" headline="Dr. Merav Opher talks about how the knowledge gained about the heliosphere can help protect astronauts from cosmic rays.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Consequences.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>One of them are cosmic rays come from outside the  heliosphere and make their way, and they are very energetic and they are hazardous for astronauts. If you are sitting on Earth, we have the Earth's magnetic fields to shield us from energetic particles and they are deflected  around. As soon as we leave Earth, send astronauts to moon, to Mars, to beyond, they are not protected. We have to have an idea how large and how intense those cosmic rays are going to be and when and how they are going affect astronauts for example.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/aurora_icon_0004_Future-data.png" medium="assets/images/What-we-expect-to-learn.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Heliosphere/Heliopause6.mp4" title="What do we expect to learn in the next several years?" headline="Dr. Merav Opher goes over the knowledge that we hope to gain as these missions continue.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/What-we-expect-to-learn.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>We expect phenomena like a reconnection to happen.  And reconnection is where the solar magnetic field, any magnetic field with opposite direction annihilates and can release energy and accelerate particles. And we expect the solar wind, the magnetic field from the Sun, to encounter the magnetic field coming outside from the interstellar medium and annihilate in certain points of the heliopause.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
</xml>