<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/ulysses.png" medium="assets/images/Ulysses_spacecraft.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Missions/ulysses.mp4" title="Ulysses" headline="A joint mission between ESA and NASA, Ulysses was designed to study the heliosphere.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/Ulysses_spacecraft.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>October 6, 1990, the Ulysses spacecraft launches aboard Space Shuttle Discovery on a mission to explore the star nearest and most important to life on Earth, the Sun. There are numerous ways in which the Sun affects the Earth. It emits this very high speed wind from the polar caps, which is what Ulysses was designed to study. At certain times this fast wind can impact the Earth. When that happens, the result are magnetic storms, and those storms lead to the aurora. They can cause damage to satellites systems, and sometimes they cause problems for the power grids on Earth. <br><br>A swing by Jupiter boosted the spacecraft above the plane of the planets and into its unique orbit around the Sun's pole, a location never before or since explored by another spacecraft. In order to get a complete view of an area around a planet, in this case you could consider the Sun a planet, if you only did that by going around the equator, you would be like trying to characterize the Earth by looking from Jamaica, say, and you'd never see there was snow on the caps. <br><br>Over the course of fifteen years and two complete orbits around the Sun, Ulysses, a joined endeavor between NASA and the European Space Agency, has provided a three-dimensional view of the system that surrounds the Sun, and extends well past the planets. The main objective is to study this vast, complex system, space system, called the Heliosphere, consists of three parts. Originates with the Sun, that whole top or part of the upper atmosphere, so-called corona, is actually expanding out into space at very high speed. And it carries magnetic fields with it, and it pushes interstellar medium, which exists throughout space between the stars away from the Sun, and it creates a huge bubble within which the solar system is located. <br><br>With over four billion miles already logged, Ulysses team plans to continue shedding more light on the Sun for some time. In the very near future, in about 2007, Ulysses will fly over the southern pole for the third time, and then a year later over the northern pole. Radioisotopic thermoelectric generators power Ulysses and can produce energy until at least 2008. It's always wonderful to do something new and different, and we've made a lot of discoveries, and it's always a treat to come in everyday knowing that the day that we'll be there and we'll be able to look at it, possibly find things that are new.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/voyager.png" medium="assets/images/VoyagerReverse.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Missions/voyager.mp4" title="Voyager" headline="The Twin Voyager spacecraft are exploring distant regions of space never before encountered by an object from Earth.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/VoyagerReverse.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Two Voyager spacecrafts were launched in 1977 on a journey to the gaint outer planets: Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune. Voyager 2 flew by Neptune in 1989, and from then on the two spacecraft were on the interstellar mission headed to the edge of interstellar space. The Voyager spacecraft will by humanity's first interstellar probes. They will be the first to go outside the region that's filled with material from our own star and the first steps into interstellar space. <br><br>Voyager 1 has reached a historic milestone. It has crossed outside of the supersonic solar wind, across what we call the Termination Shock, into a slow wind area which we call the Heliosheath, where the solar wind is much slower, much thicker, and much hotter than it was just before the shock. <br><br>Voyager now is almost a hundred times as far from the Sun as the Earth is, so the Sun is very dim, 1/10,000th as bright as it is here at Earth, and of course the planets are just specks of light in the great distance as Voyager drifts ever further into space. We listen to the two Voyager spacecraft everyday because they're measuring the magnetic fields in the solar wind, they're measuring the wind itself, how fast it's moving on Voyager 2. They're measuring the energetic particles, the fast ions which are in the outer solar system, and they're measuring the waves in the wind itself, the plasma waves. <br><br>The Termination Shock is a source of energetic electrons which stream along the magnetic field and cause the plasma, the solar wind itself, to oscillate, and that can be picked up right in the audio range where in fact the stream of electrons are telling us that we're getting very close to the Shock.  <br><br>Voyager 1 will reach the edge of interstellar space in about ten years. Voyager 2 will likely find the Shock perhaps in another three years, and then it will take it another ten years to go through the Heliosheath to reach interstellar space. We're very fortunate that the power supply on the spacecraft are radioisotope thermoelectric generators, which will continue powering the two spacecraft until at least the year 2020. It's a very exciting mission to be on because what science is about is learning new things about nature, and when you go places no spacecraft has been before, you're almost bound to learn something that no one knew before.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/stereo.png" medium="assets/images/stereo.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Missions/stereo.mp4" title="STEREO" headline="STEREO (Solar TErrestrial RElations Observatory) is a 2-year NASA mission.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/stereo.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Scientists studying solar terrestrial physics can now get a double dose of the sun through an innovative space-based mission called STEREO. STEREO, the Solar Terrestrial Relations Observatory is a NASA Space Science mission designed to obtain never-before-seen three-dimensional pictures of coronal mass ejections or CMEs from the sun. CMEs are the largest known explosions in our solar system and seriously impact electronic systems here on earth, as well as astronauts and satellites in space. <br><br>NASA scientists are very interested to learn much more about how the sun affects our modern society and our exploration of the solar system beyond our planet.  They are using new and innovative technologies in missions like STEREO to expand their knowledge of solar terrestrial physics and how the sun interacts  with the rest of the solar system.  <br><br>The STEREO mission includes two nearly identical observatories designed, built and operated by APL, the Applied Physics Laboratory,  part of Johns Hopkins University.  NASA Goddard Space Flight Center manages the twin observatory mission.  Why two spacecraft? Let's use our eyes as an example. Hold up a small object at arm's length. Look at it while alternately opening and closing each eye. It seems to jump from left to right, right?  The twin STEREO observatories take pictures of CMEs in this way with the observatories positioned at offset angles much like your eyes. The images are combined to create three-dimensional, or 3-D, images of the sun.  <br><br>Coupled with data from ground-based and low earth-orbiting observatories, STEREO's data allow the science team, led by NASA Goddard Space Flight Center, to observe in 3-D the buildup and liftoff of magnetic fields from the sun and the path of earthbound CMEs.  The twin STEREO observatories fly in orbits about the sun in front of and behind the orbit of the earth. To get both spacecraft into these critical and challenging leading and trailing orbits, mission designers have improved upon a lunar gravity assist  designed for a single spacecraft.   <br><br>It has long been known that the gravitational pull from a planetary body  can influence the shape, size, and tilt of a spacecraft's trajectory.   STEREO mission designers determined that the most efficient and cost-effective way to get the twin observatories into space was to launch them aboard a single rocket and use lunar swing-bys to place them into their respective orbits. <br><br>This is the first time lunar swing-bys have been used to place more than one  spacecraft into different orbits, something that cannot be done by the launch vehicle alone.   Before launch, the STEREO spacecraft undergo a series of in-depth  and critical tests in the clean rooms at APL and NASA Goddard Space Flight Center.  Thermal vacuum, vibration, and acoustic testing place the spacecraft systems and subsystems in similar conditions confronted in the harsh space environment. Violent launch vibrations and extreme levels of solar radiation are replicated to assure they can withstand the rigors of space throughout the life of the mission. <br><br>Each step of spacecraft development has its own testing phase. Even the smallest components are tested separately before being integrated onto the observatories to make certain everything will work right.  Once fully assembled, the observatories are tested to make sure all the individual parts work together.  These tests shake out problems that would not be repairable once the observatories are in space.  As the twin observatories are integrated onto the Delta 2 launch vehicle's third stage at Cape Canaveral Air Force Station Florida, a team of mission operators at APL in Maryland remotely monitor the health of each spacecraft. Once stacked and shrouded inside the ferring of the launch vehicle, the observatories switch to internal computer control just prior to launch. 3 2 1 engine start Lift off!<br><br>After launch, the observatories fly in an orbit from a point close to earth 	to one that extends just beyond the moon. About two months after launch, mission operators at APL synchronize spacecraft orbits directing one observatory into its earth trailing orbit. One month later, the second observatory is redirected to its position ahead of earth in its orbit around the sun. <br><br>Like a remote laboratory each observatory houses two instruments and two instrument suites for a total of 16 instruments per spacecraft. The scientific instruments come from institutions around the world. Each instrument is designed to observe a piece of our nearest star, the Sun. The STEREO mission begins a new frontier of solar exploration, visualizing the sun in ways never before seen, and allowing NASA and solar scientists to get a double dose of the Sun.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
	
	<media thumbnail="assets/images/thumbs/ibex.png" medium="assets/images/ibex.png" type="video" source="http://sunearthday.gsfc.nasa.gov/spaceweather/mobile/nasa/Videos/Missions/ibex.mp4" title="IBEX" headline="There are several boundaries at the edge of our solar system.">
		<description><![CDATA[<p><font size="24"><img src="assets/images/ibex.png" width="150" height="150" align="right"></img>Hi, my name is Dr. Eric Christian. I am the program scientist for the Interstellar Boundary Explorer or IBEX mission.<br><br>IBEX is studying the boundary between the solar wind and interstellar space.  There are several boundaries at the edge of our solar system. The closest one we call the termination shock. That's where the million mile per hour solar wind, which expands out from the sun in all directions in space, slows down, becomes more dense and starts to be diverted away before it reaches the galactic material. Beyond that is the heliopause. The heliopause is the boundary that separates material of galactic origin on the outside from material of solar origin on the inside. And even further out than that we think there is another boundary, which we call the bow shock.<br><br>Because the solar system is moving quickly through the galactic material, actually plowing through like a snow plow, we think the interaction makes a sharp jump out in front where the quickly moving in material has to slow down and start to divert away also.  You can see that really well in this animation where the solar wind is streaming out past all the planets and it's blown this bubble in interstellar space; the nearly spherical solar wind termination shock bubble. Then the solar wind slows down and starts moving back into the tail, and then the interstellar gas, which is moving very quickly up here slows down in the bow shock and moves around the solar system. <br><br>You can actually duplicate this in your own kitchen sink. If you take a stream of water and bounce it off a flat surface, what you get is a region close to the stream where the water is moving very quickly and very straight. Then suddenly it slows down and you actually see an increase in height where a shock forms in the water. That's the equivalent of the solar wind termination shock. Then beyond that shock the water is turbulent and flows down into your drain and that's the heliopause boundary out here. <br><br>Now, one of the reasons why this is important is because this solar wind that's streaming out to the heliopause pushes out galactic cosmic rays, which are radiation coming from distant parts of the galaxy, and it prevents a lot of these galactic cosmic rays from getting into the Earth or to astronauts on their way to Mars for example.  So, the solar wind pushing out sort of forms a force field if you will, that helps protects us.</p>]]></description>
	</media>
</xml>